(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-24T00:59:42.699052",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
病名恋ワズライ
[Song: Byoumei Koi Wazurai]
恋の教科書
Textbook of love,
恋の参考書
reference book of love.
キミ対策できんなら読んでもいいよ
If you want to study up on me, you can read it.
冬の香り 高くなった空
The scent of winter, the sky grown high,
隣に居たくなんの 季節のせいだよ
Wanting to be by your side, it's just the season's fault.
頼んでないのに…意地悪だ
Even though I didn't ask... how mean.
星降る夜に思い出しちゃうぞ 誤魔化せないや
On a starry night, I end up remembering, I can't brush it off.
口に出せるわけないじゃんないじゃん
There's no way I could say it out loud!
はんぶんこして…
Let's share it half and half...
恋の教科書　恋の参考書
Textbook of love, reference guide of love
キミ対策できんなら読んでもいいよ
It's fine to read up on how to handle me, you know?
冬の香り高くなった空
The winter breeze grows stronger in the sky
隣に居たいなんて季節のせいだよ
Must be because it's that season of wanting you by my side
頼んでないのに…意地悪だな
You didn't ask, yet... you're so teasing
星降る夜に思い出しちゃうな
On starry nights, I end up remembering it all
誤魔化さないやない
Don't misunderstand, alright?
Love you? No!
口に出せるわけないじゃん?ないじゃん!
There's no way I could say that out loud! No way, no way!
半分こして好きって重いものは一人じゃ重くて持てませんのよ
Sharing it half and half, "I love you" is too heavy to bear alone
半分こしてドキっと思いも誰かと一緒じゃありませんの
Sharing it half and half, a pounding heart and thoughts
友達以上になっちゃいたいのに
I want to become more than just friends
押しても引いてもなびきませんのよ
Pushing or pulling, it just won't go my way
例えば私好きになっちゃえば?
For example, if I were to fall in love with you?
例外答えも簡単でしょ!ね?
An exception's answer is simple too, right? Right?
恋って病なの
Love is like an illness
恋の作戦うまくいきません
The tactics of love just aren't going well
キミ対策しちゃうんだ…呆れちゃうでしょ?
I'm falling for your countermeasure... how pathetic, right?
乙女心変わる秋の空
A maiden's heart shifts like the autumn sky
振り向かなきゃうんと後悔しちゃうんだから
If I don't look back, I know I'll regret it later
キミが誰かに褒められてる
You're being praised by someone else
勝手に喜ぶ私ですが
And I'm happy about it on my own, but...
その“誰か”はね…
That "someone else"...
女の子だと少し複雑なんですの
If it's a girl, it gets a little complicated
半分こして好きって苦いもの全部は苦くて飲めませんのよ
Sharing it half and half, "I love you" is bitter to swallow
半分こしてドキっ痛いの薬は痛みに効きませんの
Sharing it half and half, a pounding ache in my chest
“好き”って二文字口ばっちゃいたいのに
I want to say the two words "I love you"
特別他には望みませんのよ
I don't wish for anything special beyond that
きょうから私好きになっちゃえば?
From today onwards, if I were to fall in love with you?
妄想たみには必要でしょ!ね?
That's definitely necessary in fantasies, right?
恋って病だよ
Love is just an illness
初恋は楽しんでいたけれど
My first love was fun, or so I thought,
そんなの嘘つらくて涙ばかりだった
but those were all just lies and heartbreak
でもね好きって気づけた時は嬉しかったんだ
Even so, I fell in love, and when I realized it,
半分こして好きって思いも一人じゃ重くて持てませんのよ
Sharing it half and half, "I love you" is too heavy to bear alone
半分こしてドキっと思いも特別じゃなきゃ嫌だよ
Sharing it half and half, a pounding heart and thoughts
友達以上になっちゃいたいのに
I want to become more than just friends
押しても引いてもなびきませんのよ
Pushing or pulling, it just won't go my way
誰より私好きになっちゃえば理想の彼女になってみせるよ
More than anyone else, if I were to fall in love with you,
半分こして好きって思いも一人じゃ重くて持てませんのよ
Sharing it half and half, "I love you" is too heavy to bear alone
半分こしてドキっと思いも特別じゃなきゃ嫌だよ
Sharing it half and half, a pounding heart and thoughts
友達以上になっちゃいたいのに
I want to become more than just friends
押しても引いてもなびきませんのよ
Pushing or pulling, it just won't go my way
誰より私好きになっちゃえば理想の彼女になってみせるよ
More than anyone else, if I were to fall in love with you,
いつだって君は嘲れ者だ
You've always been an outcast,
挙句に雨に降られて
Caught in the jeers and the rain.
お気に入りの傘は風で飛んでって
Your favorite umbrella blew away in the wind,
そこでのらはご苦労様と足を踏みづけていて
And you stamped your feet saying, "Good grief at that ditch."
いつもどおり君は嫌われ者だ
Just like always, you're an outcast,
なににもせずとも遠ざけられて
Kept at a distance with nothing to show for it.
努力をしてみるけれど
You try your best,
その理由なんて「なんとなく?」で
Yet the reason is just "feels like it,"
君は途方にくれて悲しんでいた
Leaving you lost and sorrowful.
ならあたしの声を使えばいいよ
Well then, you can just use my voice.
人によっては理解不能で
Some find it incomprehensible,
なんて耳障り ひどい声だって言われるけど
Calling it jarring, saying it's a terrible voice, but...
きっと君の力になれる
I'm sure I can be of help to you,
だからあたしを歌わせてみて
So let me sing for you.
そう君の 君だけの言葉でさ
Yes, with your, your very own words,
綴って 連れてって
Let's weave them, bring them along!
あたしがその思想を叫ぶから
I will cry out your thoughts.
描いて 理想を
Draw it out, your ideal!
その想いは誰にも触れさせない
Those feelings won't let anyone touch them.
ガラクタの声はそして響く
And so the Vocaloid's voice echoes on.
ありのままを不器用に繋いで
Tying your raw self clumsily,
目一杯大声を上げる
Raising our voices as loud as we can.
いつからか君は人気者だ
Before long, you became a favorite,
たくさんの人に持て囃され
Adored by so many people.
あたしも鼻が高い
I felt quite proud of it too.
でもいつからか君は変わった
But before I knew it, you had changed,
冷たくなって だけど寂しそうだった
Growing cold, yet seeming so lonely.
「もう機械の声なんてたくさんだ
"I'm sick of all these machine voices,
僕は僕自身なんだよ」って
I am myself, you see,"
ついに君は抑えきれなくなって
At last you couldn't hold it in anymore,
あたしを嫌った
And you grew to hate me.
いつもだって君は嫌われ者だ
You're always someone who gets disliked,
挙句に雨に降られて
getting caught in the rain in the end.
お気に入りの傘は風で飛んでって
Your favorite umbrella was blown away by the wind,
そこのノラはご苦労様と
and that stray over there did a great job
足を踏みつけていた
stepping all over you.
いつもどおり君は嫌われ者だ
As always, you're someone who's disliked,
なにもせずとも遠ざけられて
kept at a distance without doing anything.
努力をしてみるけれどその理由なんて「なんとなく？」で
You try making an effort, but the reason is just "for no reason at all?"
君は途方にくれて悲しんでた
and you were at a loss and feeling sad.
ならあたしの声を使えばいいよ
If so, you can just use my voice.
人によっては理解不能でなんて耳障り ひどい声だって言われるけど
People might say it's incomprehensible, grating, and a terrible voice,
きっと君の力になれる
but I can surely become your strength,
だからあたしを歌わせてみて
so try letting me sing.
そう君の 君だけの言葉でさ
Yes, with your words, and your words alone,
紡いで 連ねて
weave them, string them together,
あたしがその思想を叫ぶから
because I will shout that ideology.
描いて 理想を
Draw your ideals;
その想いは誰にも触れさせない
I won't let anyone touch those feelings.
ガラクタの歌声はそして響く
And so the voice of the junk echoes.
ありのままを不器用に繋いで 目一杯大声を上げる
Awkwardly connecting your true self, you raise your voice at the top of your lungs.
いつからか君は人気者だ
Ever since, you became popular,
たくさんの人に持て囃され あたしも鼻が高い
idolized by so many people, and I also felt proud.
でもいつからか君は変わった
But somewhere along the way, you changed,
冷たくなって だけど寂しそうだった
turning cold, yet you seemed so lonely.
「もう機械の声なんてたくさんだ 僕は僕自身なんだよ」って
"We've had enough of mechanical voices, I'm my own person,"
ついに君は抑えきれなくなって あたしを嫌った
you finally couldn't hold it back anymore and grew to hate me.
君の背後で誰かが言う 虎の威を借るキツネの癖に!
Behind you, someone says, "Acting tough on someone else's coattails!"
ねぇ 君は一人で泣いてたんだね
Hey, you were crying all alone, weren't you?
聴こえる? この声
Can you hear this voice?
あたしがその謗りをかき消すから わかってる 本当は
Because I will drown out those slanders. I know the truth—
君が誰より優しいってことを
that you're kinder than anyone else.
ガラクタの歌声はそして歌った
And so the voice of the junk sang
他の誰でもない君のために
for no one else but you,
践んでく 限界を超えて
marching past the limits.
二人はどんなにたくさんの言葉を思いついたことだろう
How many countless words must the two of us have thought of?
だけど今は何一つ思いつかなくて 歌って だけど何もかも叶わなかった
But now we can't think of a single one to sing, yet none of it came true.
そうさきっと これは夢だ 永遠に覚めない 君と会えた
Yes, surely this is a dream—a dream of meeting you from which we'll never awake.
ガラクタは幸せそうな笑顔をしたまま どれだけ呼ばれてももう動かない
With a happy smile, the junk no matter how much it's called, won't move anymore.
望んだはずの結末に
To the ending you should have wished for,
君は泣き叫ぶ 「うそだろ うそだろ」って
you cry and shout, "It's a lie, it's a lie!"
そう泣き叫ぶ 「僕は無力だ ガラクタひとつだって救やしない」って
Crying and shouting, "I'm powerless, I can't even save a single piece of junk!"
想いは涙に ぽつりぽつりとその頬を濡らす
Your feelings, bit by bit, wet your cheeks as tears.
そのとき世界は とタんにその色を大きく変える
At that moment, the world drastically changes its colors in an instant.
ああ 悲しみ喜び ぼくを一人と一つを知った
Ah, sadness and joy—I came to know myself as one and single.
言葉は歌になりこの世界をふたたび駆け巡る君のために
Words turn into songs and roam this world once again for your sake.
その気脈に石を宿して いま想いが響く
Imbuing those veins with life, feelings now resonate.
僕は無力だ ガラクタひとつだって救やしない
I'm powerless, I can't even save a single piece of junk,
想いは涙に ぽつりぽつりとその頬を濡らす
and feelings wet your cheeks as tears, drop by drop.
そのとき世界は とタんにその色を大きく変える
At that moment, the world drastically changes its colors in an instant.
ああ 悲しみ喜び ぼくを一人と一つを知った
Ah, sadness and joy—I came to know myself as one and single.
言葉は歌になりこの世界をふたたび駆け巡る君のために
Words turn into songs and roam this world once again for your sake.
その気脈に石を宿して いま想いが響く
Imbuing those veins with life, feelings now resonate.
どんな言葉を言えばいいんだろう
What kind of words should I say?
すべてのひとつの話しから 言葉を超えてこの世界をふたたび駆け巡る君のために
From every single story, transcending words, roaming this world once again for your sake.
その声に意志を宿して いま想いが響く
Imbuing that voice with will, feelings now resonate.
いま想いが響く
Feelings now resonate.
Ready Steady Go!
繊細なきみの心をかき乱してしまうものを
Things that disturb your delicate heart—
wow wow wow
吹き飛ばしたいけど まだ言葉を並べて
I want to blow them away, but still stringing words together,
あれこれ言えるほどオトナじゃなくて
not being grown-up enough to say this and that—
wow wow wow
だまってしまうだけなの
I just end up keeping silent.
be all right! 風は あした から 吹い てる
Be all right! The wind is blowing from tomorrow.
be all right! きみ の 真っ白 な シャツ を ほら
Be all right! Look at your pure white shirt,
つばさ みたい に はためかせる
fluttering like wings.
行く よ !
Let's go!
fly high fly high きっと 飛べる よ
Fly high, fly high, you can surely fly!
涙 の 跡 が いつだって 次 の スタートライン
The traces of tears are always the next starting line.
きみ と fly high fly high 憧れ て た あの 夢 まで
With you, fly high, fly high, up to that dream we longed for!
READY STEADY CAN'T HOLD ME BACK
READY STEADY GIVE ME GOOD LUCK
READY STEADY NEVER LOOK BACK
LET'S GET STARTED READY STEADY GO
吹き飛んでいく風景 転がるように前へ
The scenery blows away as if rolling forward
苦し紛れでも 標的はもう見逃さない
Even in desperation, I won't miss the target
あてにならない地図 焼いてしまえばいいさ
If the map is useless, just burn it down
埋もれた真実 この掌でつかみ取ろう
Grasping the buried truth in the palm of my hand
夢中で 早く 駆け抜けてきたんだ
I've been running through so fast in a frenzy
うるさいくらいに 張り裂けそうな鼓動の高鳴り
My heartbeat pounds so loudly it feels ready to burst
響いて 呼んでいる 君の声
Your voice echoes and calls out
ここで立ち止まるような 時間はないさ
There's no time to stop here
READY STEADY GO
心に形があるんだなら
If there is a shape to the heart,
傷ついた場所 すぐには
The wounded places won't heal right away,
手当てしてあげたいけど
But I want to tend to them.
大切なものは いつだって
Precious things are always
目には見えないのがトリックさ
Invisible—that's the trick.
君のこと知りたいのにピュアらいと
Wanting to know you, pure and bright,
かなた 空の果てとは ピュアらいと
Beyond the distant sky, pure and bright,
いつも 真っ平らな 足跡さ
Footprints always completely flat,
キャンバスへと 繋がっているの
Connected to the canvas.
行くよ ハイハイハイハイ ピットと届くよ
Here we go! Reaching straight to you!
やっと笑ってくれたんだ
You finally smiled for me.
ちょっとやそっとじゃ 魂までは奪わせない
I won't let my soul be taken away easily.
あの丘の向こうで 君に出逢えたなら 何から話そう
If I could meet you beyond that hill, what should I talk about?
そんなことばかり考えるよ
I keep thinking about such things.
READY STEADY GO
心は 走る あの空の下
My heart runs under that sky.
空回りする気持ちが 叫び出すのを止められない
I can't stop my spinning feelings from screaming out.
君まで 届け きっと後少し
Reaching you, surely just a little more,
熱く日差しが照らす この道の向こう
Beyond this road where hot sunlight shines.
READY STEADY GO
プリーズ トラスト ミー
Please, trust me.
ただ瞬き始まるんじゃない
It's not just beginning in a blink,
そこに辿り着くことを 決めた日に
On the day I decided to reach that place.
始まっていると 私は思うの
I believe it's already begun.
傷跡も涙も いつか輝く
Someday, scars and tears will shine.
大丈夫 いつでも側にいるよ
It's alright, I'll always be by your side.
つまずいたって 何度も立ち直っても
Even if you stumble, no matter how many times you recover,
君とならどんな景色も美しいと 思えることも分かっているから
I know that with you, any scenery looks beautiful.
行くよ ハイハイハイハイ ピットと届くよ
Here we go! Reaching straight to you!
涙の跡がいつだって 次のさすらい
The traces of tears will always lead to the next wanderer.
君とハイハイハイハイ 憧れてたあの夢ばる
With you, longing for that dream balloon,
続くように ブランドニューストリー
Continuing on a brand-new story.
レディ ステディ ゴー
Ready Steady Go!
君と手をつなごう
Let's hold hands with you.
やっと離れないように もっと高め合おう
Never pulling apart, let's elevate each other even more.
高く手を上げて
Raising our hands high,
レディ ステディ レディ ゴー
Ready Steady Ready Go!
あー、みんな！来てくれてありがとうございます！
Ah, everyone! Thank you so much for coming!
え、1曲目は病名恋ワズライ
Um, the first song was "Byomei Koi Wazurai",
え、2曲目を、おっつあんどえんづ
the second song was "Otsu & Enz",
3曲目はレディステディゴーでした！ありがとうございます！
and the third song was "READY STEADY GO"! Thank you!
え、今日はね、え、百鬼あやめ4周年記念ということで、
Um, today, since it's Nakiri Ayame's 4th anniversary,
え、いっぱい歌って踊らせていただきたいと思いますよ！
I wanted to sing and dance a lot for you all!
そしてそしてですね、みなさんちょっと気づ、気づきましたか？
And everyone, did you notice?
ちょっと、ステージをね、ちょっと見てほしいんですけど、
I want you to take a look at the stage.
お！お！ねえ、これ、見てください！
Oh! Oh! Hey, look at this!
この後ろにね、いっぱい付いてるんです！
There are so many things attached behind me!
端っこにはね、この大きいポヨヨが動いてて、可愛いんですよ！これちょっと見えますか？
At the edges, these big Poyoyos are moving around, and they're cute! Can you see this?
ほらポヨポヨがね、ポヨポヨしてるんですよ、これ可愛いでしょう？
Look, the Poyoyo is going poyopoyo—isn't it cute?
両端にね、置いてね、作っていただいたんです！ありがとうございます！
They placed them on both ends and made them for me! Thank you!
ね、この端っこにもね、いっぱい装飾もついていて、ね、この傘も可愛いでしょう？この目の周りにもね、傘があるんです。
And look, at the edges there are lots of decorations, and even these umbrellas are cute! Around the eyes too.
みてみて！みてみて、可愛い！可愛い！やったー！
Look, look! Look, look, so cute! So cute! Yay!
というわけでですね、あの、4周年、本当に皆さんのおかげで迎えられました、もうありがとうございます！
So, everyone, thanks to you all, I was able to celebrate my 4th anniversary. Thank you so much!
あの、日頃の感謝を込めまして、え、歌って踊っていきたいと思いますので、
To express my daily gratitude, I'm going to sing and dance for you all,
皆さん、Twitterか何かで、あの、ハッシュタグ「#百鬼あやめ4周年記念」でつぶやいていってください、
so everyone, please tweet on Twitter using the hashtag #NakiriAyame4thAnniversary.
皆さん、スクショも撮っていってくださいね、ね？
Please take screenshots too, okay?
みんな、みんな撮ってね！イエーイ！
Everyone, make sure to take lots! Yay!
という事で、これからまたゲストの方も、なんかね、登場してくるなんですけど？
With that said, guests are going to be making an appearance soon too,
あれ？あれ？なんか、ポヨヨが！
Huh? Huh? Wait, Poyoyo is...
え、かわいいの！おいで、おいで、おいで。
It's so cute! Come here, come here.
え、かわいいよ！え、見て！ちょっと、おいで、見てください、このポヨヨ。
So cute! Hey, look! Wait, come here, look at this Poyoyo.
これ持てるんですよ！かわいいでしょ？見て、ポヨヨ、ポヨヨ、ポヨヨ……
I can hold it! Isn't it cute? Look, Poyoyo, Poyoyo...
という事で、このあともね、まだゲストもたくさん来ますので、皆さん、最後も、最後も、なんか
So, there will be plenty more guests coming after this too. Everyone, at the very end, there might...
嬉しいお知らせがあるかも？ないかも？
Or might not be some happy news?
という事で、これからも見ていてください！これからも見て、ええと、見ていてください！
So please continue watching from now on! Keep watching, um, please keep watching!
バイバーイ！またねー！
Bye-bye! See you later!
誰が袖に咲く幻花
Who will bloom on sleeves as a phantom flower,
ただ そこに藍を落とした
just dropping the color indigo right there,
派手に色を溶かす夜に
in a night where colors vividly melt,
銀朱の月を添えて
accompanied by a vermilion moon.
転がるように風を切って
Cutting through the wind as if tumbling,
躓くごとに強くなった
growing stronger with every stumble.
光も痛みも怒りも全部 抱きしめて
Embracing all the light, pain, and anger,
選ばれなければ 選べばいい
if you're not chosen, then just choose.
声よ 轟け 夜 の その 向こう へ
Let your voice roar beyond the night,
涙 で 滲ん でた
where tears had blurred the view.
あんなに 遠く の 景色 まで 響き渡れ
Echo out to that distant scenery,
何 を 奏で て 誰 に 届け たく て
what are you playing, who do you want to reach,
不確か なま ま で いい
it's fine to remain uncertain.
どんなに 暗い 感情 も どんなに 長い 葛藤 も
No matter how dark the emotions, no matter how long the conflict,
歌 と 散れ 残響
sing and scatter, lingering echoes.
只一人舞う千夜 違い無い対応もすれば
Dancing all alone through a thousand nights, matching every situation,
果てしない色を明かすように 真紅の香こそあわれ
as if illuminating endless colors, the crimson fragrance is pathetic.
この先 どんな辛い時も 口先よりも胸を張って
From now on, in any difficult time, puff out your chest rather than just talking,
描いた 夢の 明かり を 全部 辿る だけ
and just follow every light of the dream you drew.
逃げ出す為 ここに来た んじゃないだろ
We didn't come this far just to run away, right?
選ばれなければ 選べばいい
If you're not chosen, then just choose.
声を枯らして燃える華のように 魔界を照らしたら
Like a flower burning with a hoarse voice, when you illuminate the demon world,
曖昧すぎる世界も譜面にして
turn even this overly vague world into a musical score,
夜を数えて朝を描くような鮮やかな音を鳴らす
and ring out a vivid sound that counts the nights and paints the morning.
どんなに深い後悔も どんなに高い限界も
No matter how deep the regret, no matter how high the limit,
掻き消して残響
erase them all with lingering echoes.
夜を数えて朝を描くような
Counting the nights, painting the mornings,
鮮やかな音を鳴らす
ringing out a vivid sound.
どんなに深い後悔も
No matter how deep the regret,
どんなに高い限界も
no matter how high the limit,
掻き消して残響
erase them all with lingering echoes.
声をからしてもえる花のように 闇夜を照らして
Like a flower burning with a hoarse voice, illuminating the dark night,
曖昧すぎる世界も 不鮮明にして
making even this overly vague world unclear,
夜を数えて朝を描くような 鮮やかな眼をならせ
count the nights, paint the morning, and open your vivid eyes.
どんなに深紅な後悔も どんなに高い限界も
No matter how deep the crimson regret, no matter how high the limit,
かきけして残響
erase them all with lingering echoes.
どんなに深紅な後悔も どんなに高い限界も
No matter how deep the crimson regret, no matter how high the limit,
かきけして残響
erase them all with lingering echoes.
あーー！楽しかったなー！
Ahhh, that was so fun!
楽しかった！
So fun!
あやめ、4周年おめでとう！
Ayame, happy 4th anniversary!
ありがとうー！やったー！4周年だ！
Thank you! Yay! It's the 4th anniversary!
あやめのんか、今日よかった、かわいいね。
Ayame, your outfit today is so nice and cute.
そうなの、気づいてくれた？
That's right, did you notice?
あのね、ホロライブサマーとは ちょっと違った色の浴衣なんですよー。
You see, it's a yukata in a slightly different color from Hololive Summer.
そうそう、お花の色のね、いい感じにあやめの髪の毛の色とマッチしているね。
That's right, the flower colors match Ayame's hair color nicely.
え、もしかして、あれ、みおちゃんも違うじゃないですか。
Wait, could it be... Mio, isn't yours different too?
あ、ちょっと違うかもしれないですね。
Ah, mine might be a bit different.
なんかちょっと大人って感じですね。
It feels kind of grown-up.
ああ、本当に。
Yeah, really.
あら、ちょっと水色とか選んじゃった。
Oh, I ended up picking light blue.
ああ、いいね。なんかみおちゃんって赤ってイメージがあったから、なんかちょっと新鮮な感じ、水色も。
Ah, nice! I usually associate Mio with red, so light blue feels a bit fresh too.
本当に？おしゃれ。
Really? It's stylish.
ちょっとね、うん。花火大会出てるみたいな感じだね。なんかちょっとね、照れるね。
Yeah... it feels like we're at a fireworks festival. It's kind of embarrassing, you know.
あ、えへへへ。
Ah, hehehe.
なんか曲中もね、花火上がってたから、ああ！すごい！
And fireworks were going off during the song too! Wow, amazing!
花火大会や！やばいや！
It's a fireworks festival! This is awesome!
すごい！
Amazing!
えみおちゃん、花火大会だ！
Mio, it's a fireworks festival!
あはははは！
Ahahaha!
来たぞ！花火大会や！二人だけの花火大会だよ！
It's here! A fireworks festival, just the two of us!
みおちゃんと行きたいと思ってたんだよね。
I've been wanting to go with Mio.
ええ、嬉しいな、そんなこと言ってくれるなんて。
Aww, I'm so happy you'd say that.
曲、あ、お、曲、今日はさ、なんでこの曲選んだの？
By the way, why did you choose this song today?
え、あのね、残響散歌を絶対にみおちゃんに似合うって、もともと思ってたのね、もう。
Well, I originally thought 'Zankyou Sanka' would totally suit Mio.
え、そうなの？そう、かっこいいのみおちゃんと歌いたいなと思って、ね、ちょっとね、頑張ってお誘いしました。
Oh, really? Yeah, I wanted to sing a cool song with Mio, so I worked hard to invite you.
え、ありがとう！ありがとう！
Ah, thank you! Thank you!
え、でもみおちゃん覚えてくれたんだよね、今回。
And Mio even memorized it for this time, right?
そうなんだよ！もう誘われたから頑張ろうって思って。嬉しい！そう、でも覚える機会になったからすごい嬉しかった。ありがとうね。
That's right! Once I was invited, I decided to do my best. I'm so glad! It gave me a chance to learn it, which made me really happy. Thanks!
よがね、いい機会を作れました。うん、よかった！よかった！
I'm glad we made a good opportunity out of it. Yeah, I'm so glad!
ありがとう、ありがとう！めちゃくらかっこよかった。
Thank you so much! It was super cool.
で、このあと、お嫁を、どうするんだ？
So, what are we doing after this?
このあとはね、ちょっと夜の、ソロがあります。
After this, there's a nighttime solo part.
ソロがあるの？え、そうなの。
A solo? Oh, is that so?
え、でもね、あとでまた、みおちゃんと、歌う、歌って踊る、踊るコラボがあるの。
Well, later on, Mio and I have another singing and dancing collab.
そう、そう。ちょっとうちらも着替えてくるからさ。
That's right. We're going to go change clothes real quick.
歌いに行こ、いこ、いこ、いこ、いこ！
Let's go sing, let's go, let's go!
いこ、いこ！いこ、いこ、いこ、いこ、いこ、いこ！
Let's go, let's go!
響いたメロディーが始まりを告げて
The echoing melody heralds the beginning,
終わらない夢を描くよ
painting an endless dream.
見上げた空に映った虹を追いかけ
Chasing the rainbow reflected in the sky we looked up at,
転んで笑い合っていたね
we'd fall and laugh together.
思い出に残るあの景色は
That memorable scenery
深くで綺麗だね
is deeply, breathtakingly beautiful.
不思議なほどに魅せられた君の声
Your voice captivated me so mysteriously,
始まってきっとその時から恋に落ちたなんて単純だ
from that very moment we began, falling in love is so simple.
だけど仕方がないでしょう
But I suppose it can't be helped,
例えばいつか信じていたものに裏切られたとしてもその時は
even if someday we were betrayed by what we believed in.
君の声がどこまでも届いて
Your voice reaches everywhere,
無数の想い重なり合って
as countless feelings overlap.
痛みをさあ乗り越えて行こう
Come on, let's overcome the pain together.
響いたメロディーが世界を駆け行く
The echoing melody races across the world,
未来を信じられるよ
making me believe in the future.
勇気に変えてゆく君と並んで
Turning it into courage, standing side by side with you,
同じ景色を見て手を伸ばそうそこに Future Sky
let's look at the same scenery and reach out to the Future Sky.
響いたメロディーが世界を駆け行く
The echoing melody races across the world,
未来を信じられるよ
making me believe in the future.
勇気に変えてゆく君と並んで
Turning it into courage, standing side by side with you,
同じ景色を見て
let's look at the same scenery
手を伸ばそうそこに Future Sky
and reach out to the Future Sky.
いつからだろう苦しいほどの愛情
Since when has this agonizing affection
無欲さそんなルージュ抱えて
and unselfishness embraced this rouge?
答えのない戸惑いを巡りで
Wandering through unanswered perplexities,
それはそう君のせいだよ
that's right, it's all because of you.
いつでも人は一人で生きるには
Whenever people try to live alone,
抱えきれないほどの苦しみ背負って
they bear more suffering than they can handle.
だから誰かのために生きるそんな気になれることも必要
That's why we need to feel like living for someone else.
戸惑いを手放せない
We can't let go of this confusion.
描いたストーリーがこの星を巡る
The story we drew goes around this star,
明日を愛してゆく
learning to love tomorrow.
希望に連なる君の...
Connected to hope, your...
一人じゃないんだって今思えた
I realized just now that I'm not alone.
飛んで跳ねて晴れて咲いて
Leaping, bounding, clearing, blooming—
夢の粒を集めて君は「終われないよ」って叫んだ
Gathering grains of dreams, you cried out, "It can't end here!"
とびきりの怯えを撒き散らして
Scattering exceptional fear all around,
駆け出しの勇気を突き刺すぜ
piercing straight through your budding courage!
君は君に染まれ眩しい日々よ
Bathe in your true colors, dazzling days!
もうなにも失わないよ
I won't lose anything ever again!
絶対に絶対に離れ離れしないから
Because we will never, ever be apart,
もう怖くないって胸張って前向いて
with head held high and facing forward, no longer scared!
「頼んだよ」って託されたんだ
"I'm counting on you," I was entrusted with it—
声に出せない「ごめん」と一緒に
along with an unspoken "I'm sorry."
強くって儚い気持ち包まれてく
Enveloped in feelings both strong and fleeting,
でもオレは負ける気はしない
yet I have no intention of losing!
絶対に絶対に離れ離れしないから
Because we will never, ever be apart,
そう伝え合うんだ “確かな温もりだけ”
let's convey "only this certain warmth."
オレはオレに染まれ眩しい日々よ
Bathe in your true colors, dazzling days!
もうなにも失わないよ
I won't lose anything ever again!
全力で走れ！今未来を奏で
Run with all your might! Play the future now!
なあそうしたら過去だって変わるから
Hey, because if you do, even the past will change!
言えぬ言葉の数を数えていては
If you keep counting the words you couldn't say,
(一、二、三、四、五、六、七、八と)
(One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight...)
小さなこの両手じゃ数えきれない
you won't be able to count them all with these small hands.
愛の歌が今も生まれる
A song of love is still being born right now.
頭隠していても
Even if you hide your head,
角も尻尾も隠せない止められない
you can't hide your horns or your tail; it's unstoppable!
覗いては雲隠れ乙女の恋詩歌
Peeking in and hiding in the clouds—a maiden's love poem.
気が付かずに気が付いてよ
Without realizing it, please realize it—
秘密の心は
my secret heart is
五月の闇
the darkness of May.
その向こうで舞い踊る
Dancing and spinning just beyond it!
恋しそう君へ届くように
Hoping it reaches you, my yearning beloved—
側で聞こえてしまう程鳴り響く
Sounding so close it can be heard,
(ドキドキンドキドキドキンドキッ！)
(Thump, thump, beating fast!)
心寒くても増すばかりで
even if the heart feels cold, it only grows stronger,
クラクラする程の感情
feelings so dizzying and intense.
目線逸していても
Even if you look away,
角も尻尾も隠せない止められない
you can't hide your horns or your tail; it's unstoppable!
夢見ては雲越えて乙女の恋詩歌
Dreaming beyond the clouds—a maiden's love poem.
愛さずに愛しててよ
Love me without needing to be loved back!
裏腹心は五月の闇
My contradictory heart is the darkness of May.
その向こうに何を見る
What do you see beyond it?
愛しそう君へ届くように
Hoping it reaches you, my yearning beloved—
真心の鬼火そっと灯す
softly lighting the ghost fire of true sincerity.
アイラブユウの数光らせば
If you make the "I love you"s shine bright,
化かしてあげましょうほら夢中
I'll put a spell on you—look, you're enchanted!
高く声上げりゃ遠く鳴らせ
Raise your voice high and let it ring afar,
どこに居たって遠く響かせ
echoing far no matter where you are!
物怪乙女の三人衆
The trio of monster maidens,
そこ退けそこ退け我等が通る
step aside, step aside as we pass through!
願いばいつかは晴れよと
Praying that someday the skies will clear—
闇に隠せし恋心
Concealing this romantic heart in the dark...
雲の切れ間に明かりさす
Light shines through the gaps in the clouds.
今の時に
In this very moment...
見つめれば隠してはおけない恋情しずく
If I gaze at you, this droplet of passion cannot be hidden.
触れないで抱き寄せてよ
Don't just touch me, pull me close.
素直になれたら五月の闇
If I could be honest, in the darkness of May...
君だけに歌う歌を
A song I sing only for you.
恋しと君へと伝うように
So that my love reaches out to you...
愛しと君へと届くように
So that my affection reaches you...
宵の口よ 新らたよの夢のあとに 燃え尽きろ 下げろよ
In the early evening, after the fleeting dream, burn out completely.
空の鏡 釣る君へ 世用に応じて ごゆるりと
To you, hanging like a mirror in the sky, taking things easy as the world requires.
ひらりひらり 舞い散るよ 言の葉は途切れず
Fluttering and scattering down, the words never cease.
一平の想いすら 月夜の熱に焦がれ
Even a fleeting thought scorches in the moonlight's heat.
朧げに染まる月夜は知らぬ間に慣れ初め
The vaguely dyed moonlit night quietly turns into romance.
まるでつばき この愛を叶えさせてよ
Like a camellia, let this love come true.
浮き世草 迷いじゃないと感じさせて
Make me feel this floating world's weed is no hesitation.
ひしと咲く 永久の相棒 秘密のだけを重ねて
Blooming tightly, an eternal partner, stacking up only secrets.
燃えいづる 春となれ探しではまだ言いづこ
Becoming a blazing spring, searching still feels hard to say.
はかなく 歌え つばき 歌え つばき
Ephemerally sing, camellia, sing, camellia.
蕾を美しく 想いを奏でて 歌え つばき 歌え つばき
Make the buds beautiful, play our feelings, sing, camellia, sing!
眠るびとよ 花の数だけ 集めた甘い思いを
Sleeping one, gathering sweet memories equal to the number of flowers.
折り重なって つづる明日へ 切ない奇跡をごしょうも
Piling up towards tomorrow, granting a bittersweet miracle.
左利らは 春よの女王にのまれ 先誇れ最高潮で 心を赤く染める
Left-handed flowers swallowed by the queen of spring, proudly blooming at their peak, dyeing hearts red.
最後まで 乱れずただ一途な愛で 歌い つばき
Until the very end, unflinchingly with single-minded love, sing, camellia.
鳴り飾る 甘い言葉じゃ 本当の想いは奥の奥
Sweet words of decoration—true feelings are deep within.
ただ 君を求め 赤く染めた この場所が す
Just seeking you, dyeing it red, this place is...
ひらひら 舞い散るよ 侘び寂びを破る衝動
Fluttering and scattering, an impulse breaking wabi-sabi.
かがせた 言葉すら なが夜の中に消えど
Even the words made to shine vanish into the long night.
気付いてよ 翳む月は すでに心に染まる
Realize it, the dimming moon already stains the heart.
まるでつばき この愛を叶えさせてよ
Like a camellia, let this love come true.
浮き世草 迷いじゃないと信じさせて
Make me believe this floating world's weed is no hesitation.
ひしと咲く 永久の相棒 秘密のだけを重ねて
Blooming tightly, an eternal partner, stacking up only secrets.
燃えいづる 春となれ探しではまだ言いづこ
Becoming a blazing spring, searching still feels hard to say.
はかなく 歌え つばき 歌え つばき
Ephemerally sing, camellia, sing, camellia.
蕾を美しく 想いを奏でて 歌え つばき 歌え つばき
Make the buds beautiful, play our feelings, sing, camellia, sing!
つぼみ 美しく 思いを奏でて 歌え つばき 歌え つばき
Beautiful buds, playing our feelings, sing, camellia, sing!
あやめ４周年おめでとう！
Happy 4th anniversary, Ayame!
４周年！ よっしゅねーん！
4th anniversary! Yoshu-neen!
ねぇ 楽しんでる?
Hey, are you enjoying it?
楽しんでるよね
You're enjoying it, right?
なんかこういうさ、フリートークでせーのって言うことがあんまりなかったからさ
We rarely get to do a joint greeting in free talk.
確かに、なかった、新鮮ですね
That's true, we don't. It feels fresh.
新鮮です
It's fresh.
新鮮ですね、ふふふ
It really is, haha.
改めまして、よろしくお願いいたします！
Once again, nice to meet you!
ちょっとね、先ほども呼んでいただいたんですけれども
We were called just a little while ago, but...
あ、そうだよね。そうだよね、2回だよ、やったー
Ah, that's right. Twice! Yay!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ちょっと、太陽バッチでーす
We're wearing fluffy sun badges.
ぽかぽかっちゃったね
We got all warmed up.
今日3人では、連称シーカーと、え、つばきを
Today, the three of us sang Renshou Seeker and Tsubaki.
歌いました。だけどつばきかね、なんとここ、YouTubeでは初！初お披露目でした！
And Tsubaki made its very first YouTube debut here!
うれしい！そうだそうだ
So happy! That's right.
やっとだよ、やっとだよもう！
Finally, finally!
ねえ、初めて見る人間さんもちるんじゃないですかね？
I'm sure there are humans seeing it for the first time!
絶対いるね
Definitely.
ねえ、そうだね
Yeah, true.
どうだったかな?
How was it?
どうだった?どうだった?どうでした?
How was it? How was it?
どうでした?初めてのね YouTubeはどうだったのかな?
How was your first YouTube experience?
ねえ、これ難しいんだよね、意外とね
It's surprisingly difficult, you know.
意外とね
Surprisingly.
そう、手足が動くの難しいんだよね
Yeah, moving hands and feet is hard.
リハね、ちょっと頑張って、間違ってないといいんですけども、ね、ちょっといいとこだけ見てください
We worked hard in rehearsals, please focus on the good parts.
あ、間違えしちゃったなと思ったら ちょっと見なかったことにして、見なかったことにしてください
If you think we messed up, please just pretend you didn't see it.
なんとかして、もう、なんとかしてもらってますのでね、いいとこだけお願いします！
We managed somehow, so please just look at the good parts!
お願いします！
Please!
そしてなんと、今日後ろになんか
And also, today behind us...
あ、そうなんですよ、見て。さっきもなんかいたけども
Ah, that's right, look. Something was there earlier too.
そう、4周年記念で、よよよ、おやおや、なんとかだ！
Yes, for the 4th anniversary, it's... whatever this is!
おいおい、めっちゃ動いてるよ！
Hey hey, it's moving so much!
なんかさ、このぽよよよさ、リハではね、もっと違かったんだよね。え、そうなんだよね、確かにに
In rehearsal it was a bit different. True.
実はね、あの、リハーサルではサングラスかけてて、あ、これだ！これかけててね
Actually, in rehearsals it was wearing sunglasses. Ah, this!
サングラスも、あ！動くんだよ、動くんだよ、動くの！やばい！もう、これ
The sunglasses also move! So crazy!
え、でも、なくしたよね、これ、リハでね。え、そうなんだよね、実はリハーサルの時は、これ動いてたんだけど
Ah, but we lost this in rehearsal, right? It was moving.
あまりにも存在感が大きすぎて、後ろでずっとカメラに絶対入るぽよみたいななんて
It had too much presence, constantly getting into the camera.
笑ってできなくなっちゃう、笑ってできなくなっちゃったので、本番ではね、ちょっと外していただいたんです
We couldn't stop laughing, so we took it off for the actual show.
そう、ちらちらちらちら、かわいいけどね、かわいいけどね、ええ
Yeah, flickering, though it's cute.
いや、よきですけれども
Well, it's nice.
じゃあ、これから、ちょっとこのあとどうする?焼肉でも食べにいく?
So, what should we do next? Go eat yakiniku?
焼肉いきたい！お腹すいちゃった
I want yakiniku! I got hungry.
行きたいんだけど、まだこのあともあるんです
We want to go, but there's more after this.
このあともあるの?まだ、あるぞ！
There's more? Still more!
じゃあ、このあともうちわでちょっと見守ってよか
Then, please watch over us with your uchiwa fans after this too.
え、じゃあちょっとふたりで見守ってもらおっかな。え、いいの?いいよ！
Oh, then can you two watch over us? Is that okay? Sure!
じゃあちょっとふたりで見守ってもらおっかな
Then let's have you two watch over us.
がんばるぞー、ありがとうね、売ってるぜ、がんばるよ
We'll do our best, thanks!
じゃあ、あっちでみもっとこか。オッケー行くか、せーの！
Then let's watch from over there. Okay, let's go, ready, set!
ありがとうね、ばいばい、またね！ばいばい！
Thank you, bye bye, see you later!
わっちゅーげっちゅー 熱烈うぉんちゅー
Watchu getchu, passionate want you
しゅきしゅぎて弾けたvividマインド
A vivid mind bursting with too much love
ルーレット グッドスタート きっとゲット 1等！
Roulette, good start, surely get first prize!
1等！1等！
First prize! First prize!
永久センキョー ときめきknock you
Eternal election, heartbeat knock you
1ミリの隙間に出ビーム
Shooting a beam through a 1mm gap
ラブスタンプ 全部コンプ 運勢アップ
Love stamp, all completed, fortune up
いいぞ！いいぞ！
Great! Great!
いいぞ！いいぞ！せーの！
Great! Great! Ready, set!
だって今日はゴッドメンタル
Because today I have god mental
勇ましきチャレンジャー
A courageous challenger
ちょっとだけセンチメンタル
Just a little sentimental
だいしゅーだいいしゅき ♡ 123 ハイ！
Dai-shuu dai-shuki ♡ 1 2 3 High!
まみまめもめも 目もみれないの
Mami mame momemo, I can't even look you in the eye
たちつてとてとて 手と手が触れて
Tachitsu tetotete, our hands touch
だいしゅーだいいしゅきになれ！
Become deeply, deeply in love with me!
もっときゅきゅっ きゅっ キュート 強制ラヴ！
More kyu-kyu, cute, forced love!
あのね クリオネ 透け てるハート
You know, clione, a see-through heart
でもね この胸 見透かさないで
But don't see right through this chest
だいしゅーだいいしゅきになれ！
Become deeply, deeply in love with me!
アタシじゃないなんて終わってんね
Saying it's not me is so over
わっちゅーげっちゅー 蜜月うぉんちゅー
Watchu getchu, honeymoon want you
しゅきしゅぎて空ぶるcutieマインド
A cutie mind swinging and missing from too much love
ルーレット ちょっとストップ 一旦休憩
Roulette, little stop, short break
いや！いや！いや！でも！
No! No! No! But!
せーの！
Ready, set!
だって今日は求めてる
Because today I'm seeking
麗しきチャレンジャー
A graceful challenger
ハート描いた オートメーション
Automation drawing a heart
だいしゅーだいいしゅき ♡ 123 ハイ！
Dai-shuu dai-shuki ♡ 1 2 3 High!
まみまめろめろ にして欲しいの
Wanting you to make me dizzy with love
なにぬねこねこ 恋のコネクト
Nani nu neko neko, connection of love
だいしゅーだいいしゅきになれ！
Become deeply, deeply in love with me!
もっときっきっきっしゅ 強制ラブ！
More ki-ki-kishu, forced love!
あのね マリオネット あやつるレディー
You know, marionette, controlling lady
でもね それもね 悪くはないね
But you know, even that isn't bad
だいしゅーだいいしゅきになれ！
Become deeply, deeply in love with me!
アタシじゃないなんて終わってんね
Saying it's not me is so over
まみまめろめろ にして欲しいの
Wanting you to make me dizzy with love
なにぬねこねこ 恋のコネクト
Nani nu neko neko, connection of love
だいしゅーだいいしゅきになれ！
Become deeply, deeply in love with me!
もっときっきっきっしゅ 強制ラブ！
More ki-ki-kishu, forced love!
あのね マリオネット あやつるレディー
You know, marionette, controlling lady
でもね それもね 悪くはないね
But you know, even that isn't bad
だいしゅーだいいしゅきになれ！
Become deeply, deeply in love with me!
アタシじゃないなんて終わってんね
Saying it's not me is so over
ふれんどりーなふりして周波数を乱さないで
Acting friendly, don't disturb the frequency.
異次元の魅惑のリップ ディ・ア・リ・ナ・ビ・ラ
Dimensional lips of fascination, D-I-A-R-I-N-A-V-I-R-A
まみむめも目も見れないの
Can't even see m-a-mi-mu-me-mo...
たちつてと手と手が触れて
Hands touching t-a-chi-tsu-te-to...
だいきゅーだいしゅきになれ！
Become totally head-over-heels!
もっときゅきゅきゅきゅっと強制ラブ！
More tight, tight, forced love!
あのねクリオネ透けてるハート
Hey, a transparent clione heart,
でもねこの胸見逃さないで
but don't miss out on my chest!
だいきゅーだいしゅきになれ！
Become totally head-over-heels!
アタシじゃないなんて終わってんね！！
Saying it's not me is so over!!
まみむめも目も見れないの
Can't even see m-a-mi-mu-me-mo...
たちつてと手と手が触れて
Hands touching t-a-chi-tsu-te-to...
だいきゅーだいしゅきになれ！
Become totally head-over-heels!
もっときゅきゅきゅきゅっと強制ラブ！
More tight, tight, forced love!
あのねクリオネ透けてるハート
Hey, a transparent clione heart,
でもねこの胸見逃さないで
but don't miss out on my chest!
だいきゅーだいしゅきになれ！
Become totally head-over-heels!
アタシじゃないなんて終わってんね
Saying it's not me is so over!
ありがとー！ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you!
うれしいうれしやったやった！
So happy, so happy, yay yay!
うれしい、ありがとうございます来てくれて。
I'm so happy, thank you for coming.
あやめ先輩とこうやってお話し...一人？
Talking with Ayame-senpai like this... alone?
一緒にコラボレーションするのは初めてなんですよ！
Collaborating together is actually our first time!
えー！やったー！
Eh! Yay!
こないださ、めちゃめちゃうるさい
The other day, you were super noisy...
いやいや、違う違う、違う違う違う。
No no, wait, that's wrong, wrong, wrong.
いや本当にね、あやめ先輩に誘ってもらった時、え、マジ？と思って。
Seriously though, when Ayame-senpai invited me, I was like, "Seriously?!"
本当にあやめ先輩に誘ってもらって、私、誘いたかったんです！
I really wanted Ayame-senpai to invite me!
めちゃくちゃるさかったて、え、かわいいちゃん可愛い曲を歌いたいってね
You were super loud saying "I want to sing cute songs with Ayame-chan!"
え、誘ってくれてましたよね？　そうそう！言ってくれる、言ってくれる...
Eh, you invited me, right? That's right! You kept saying it...
そう、やりたくて、ねえ、ちょっとクロールちゃんに頑張って誘いして、ねえ、一緒に踊ってもらいました！やったー！
Yeah, I wanted to do it, so I tried my best to invite Chloe-chan, and we danced together! Yay!
ありがとう！やったやったやったやれた！
Thank you! Yay, yay, we finally did it!
でも、あやめ先輩がさ、そこ本音のこと大好きのなのは、そこ本音もう元々知ってたっていうか
But, Ayame-senpai, about "Daishuki" (loving you), did you already know about that?
あやめ先輩！あやめ先輩！大好きですもんね！
Ayame-senpai! Ayame-senpai! You love it, don't you!
これからもっと仲良くなりますよね？もっとちょっと良く分からない！楽しかった！ありがとう！
We'll get even closer from now on, right? I don't really get it! That was fun! Thank you!
あ、ちょっと君に伝えたい 何かがあったような携帯
Ah, I have something I want to tell you, like a phone with a message.
真逆の踊るベール サカサマだと知って 好意とは魅惑のプログラム
Dancing in the opposite veil, knowing it's upside down, affection is a fascinating program.
ただ差し詰めここから行き着くは愛
Just summing it up, where we end up is love.
アイデンティティ それは嗜好のアイデンティティ
Identity, that is the identity of preference.
アイデンティティ 唸れ 君一人のせい
Identity, roar, it's all your fault alone.
まだ捨てないで待って それは一つ二つのデスティニー
Don't throw it away yet, wait, that's one or two destinies.
繋げてハッピー 落ちる 流星星と歪なあの星
Connecting to happy, falling shooting stars and that distorted star.
重なる面影に寄り添う そっと君に寄り添う
Nestling close to overlapping shadows, softly nestling close to you,
弾けだす視界 胸に飛び込むハート 光るあなたのアイデンティティ
bursting field of vision, a heart jumping into my chest, your glowing identity.
難儀プライド飛び込めデンジャラス
Troublesome pride, jump into dangerous,
さっそく羽ばたく強気な狂気と遊んで 裏切りを涙で頂戴
play with fluttering strong-willed madness, receive betrayal with tears.
ランブラララト足取りデンジャラス 背後隠れた二人に見つけて
Ramblaralato footsteps dangerous, focus on the two hidden behind,
ようやっと見つけた 不思議な正体
finally found, the mysterious identity.
きっと恋とは真逆のプログラム ただ差し詰めここから行き着くは愛
Surely love is the exact opposite program, just summing it up, where we end up is love.
アイデンティティ それは希望のアイデンティティ
Identity, that is the identity of hope.
アイデンティティ 唸れ 君一人のせい
Identity, roar, it's all your fault alone.
あ、ちょっと君に伝えたい
Ah, just a sec, there's something I wanna tell you
何かがあったような
Right on the tip of my tongue, I swear...
けっかい真逆の踊るベール
Swaying by a thread, truly, what a sight
サカサマだと知って
Knowing it's upside down
好意とは魅惑のプログラム
Affection is a seductive program
ただ差し詰めここから行き着くは愛
Leading straight to love in the end
アイデンティティ それは嗜好のアイデンティティ
Identity - whatever you like, it's my identity
アイデンティティ 冒涜せよ 君一人のせい
Identity - show your teeth, it's all on you
まだ捨てないで待って それは一つ二つのデスティニー
Don't throw it away yet, it's our destiny
繋げてハッピー 落ちる流れ星と歪みなあの星
Connect to happy, shooting stars and crooked stars
重なる面影に寄り添う そっと君に寄り添う
Clinging to overlapping shadows, close to you
弾けだす視界 胸に飛び込むハート 光るあなたのアイデンティティ
A bursting view, heart leaping in, your shining identity
難儀プライド飛び込めデンジャラス サッと羽ばたく強気の狂気と
Dive into dangerous pride, soaring with bold madness
そんで裏切り お涙頂戴
And betrayal, eliciting tears
はーい！あやめ先パイ4周年おめでとうございます！
Ha-! Ayame-senpai, congratulations on your 4th anniversary!
ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much! Thank you!
やっと来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for finally coming!
今日はルイちゃんに来ていただきました！
Today we invited Lui-chan to join us!
いつも会ってるけど3Dで並ぶのは初めてですね！
We always meet up, but lining up in 3D is a first!
こないだルイちゃんのアイデンティティを聞いたんですよ。
The other day, I heard Lui-chan's "Identity".
ルイちゃんのお歌用の、そう、あれね、めちゃ良くてね！
For your singing, and it was so good!
「あぁ、歌いたい一緒に！」って思ったので今回ちょっと呼ばせていただきました。
I thought "Ah, I want to sing it together!", so I invited you.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
でもめちゃくちゃギャップ萌えでめちゃっかっこよかったですね！
It had such a gap moe and was super cool!
うちらのハーモニー最高でしたよ！
Our harmony was the best!
あやめ先パイ最高だったな！
Ayame-senpai was the best!
あれ？今あやめ先パイって言った？
Huh? Did you just say "Ayame-senpai"?
はい。あやめ先パイって呼んでますからね。
Yes. I call you Ayame-senpai, you know.
いつもと違くない？
Isn't that different from usual?
いつも「あやめちゃーん」って呼んでるじゃん！
You usually call me "Ayame-chan"!
今日3Dだからちょっといいとこ見せようとしてるんでしょ！
You're trying to show your good side because it's 3D today!
いつも通り「あやめちゃん」って呼んでくれても大丈夫ですよ！
You can just call me "Ayame-chan" like always!
じゃああやめちゃん、よろしくお願いします！
Then Ayame-chan, please take care of me!
えー、「土曜の女」、土曜の女って誰なの？
Um, "Saturday Woman"... who is the Saturday woman?
ルイちゃん、「土曜の女」って誰なの？
Lui-chan, who is the "Saturday woman"?
この混沌とした令和のインターネットを照らす一筋の光
This is a supernova rising upon the chaotic modern cyberspace
電子の海を漂うオタクに笑顔を
Bringing happiness to all geeks of the internet
未来の平和をお約束 躁鬱だけどまかせとけ
I promise eternal peace, erratic but leave it to me
インターネット・エンジェル ただいま降臨
Internet Angel, descending right now!
社会をやめろ 家族をやめろ 人間関係をやめろ
Quit society, quit family, quit human relationships
今すぐ薄暗い部屋で青白いライトを浴びろ
Bathe under the pale light in a dim room right now
大丈夫こんなこと全部上書きするからね
Don't worry, I'll overwrite all of this
現実よりも crazy for you
More than in reality, crazy for you
おかしくなりそうなほど情報過多のインターネット
Overwhelming, mind-blowing social network
今たすけてあげるよダーリンダーリン
I'm gonna save you now, darling darling
ウソはウソであると見抜けるしこの愛は暴走しちゃうし
Lies are obviously lies, and this love runs wild
壊れてしまうけど
Even if it ends up breaking down
考えなくていいんだよ もうすぐ楽になるからね
You don't have to think, you'll soon feel at ease
脳内に乱反射する poison radio よりも甘いよ
Sweeter than the poison radio reflecting in my mind
いいねよくないね キミにとっては毒だね
Like it, dislike it, it's poison for you
いいねよくないね それでも飲むんだね
Like it, dislike it, but you'll drink it anyway
いいねよくないね 二人のヒミツだね
Like it, dislike it, it's our secret
わたしだけ見ててね
Just keep looking at me
まるで天使のように微笑む 強めの幻覚 internet girl
Smiling like an angel, a strong illusion internet girl
そして悪魔みたいにささやきかける アナタだけの needy girl
And whispering like a demon, your only needy girl
アナタだけの needy girl
Your only needy girl
浅い眠りと承認欲求のオーバードーズ
Shallow sleep and an approval-seeking overdose.
脳天直撃するわたしたちだけの宗教とヒカリ
Our sole religion and light striking straight to the brain.
倫理より激しく生きた宇宙すら侵食する恋
A love living fiercer than ethics, eroding even the universe.
何度も送られる毒電波を優しさだけで包んで
Wrapping the repeatedly sent toxic waves in pure kindness.
逆さまのコンピュータと断片的なカウンセリング
With an inverted computer and fragmented counseling.
きらめく屋上で奏でてた夢見心地の旋律
The dreamy melody played on the sparkling rooftop.
夕暮れ時にさよならの練習をして
Practicing goodbyes at twilight.
壊して愛して許して狂って狂って狂って狂って甘く狂わせて！
Break it, love it, forgive it, go crazy, crazy, crazy, drive me sweetly crazy!
揺らぎ始める世界
The world begins to waver,
曖昧になる風景
the scenery turning vague.
あなただけが映っているメモリー
A memory reflecting only you.
神様なんていないよ
There is no such thing as God.
このふざけたインターネットは七色のサイケデリック
This ridiculous internet is a rainbow psychedelic.
SNSという瓶詰めジュースに救済を
Bringing salvation to the bottled juice called SNS.
過去の歴史は見ないふり あなたのためなら即座に
Pretending not to see past history, instantly if it's for you.
インターネット・エンジェル かわいさいじょう
Internet Angel, maximum cuteness!
まるで天使のように抱きつく
Embracing you just like an angel,
強めの願望 インターネット
with strong desire, Internet.
そして悪魔みたいにキスする アナタだけの
And kissing you like a demon, your very own...
アナタだけのニーディガー
your very own needy girl!
ANGEL
はーい！
Hii!
おっ おっ おっ おっ なんだなんだ？
Oh, oh, what is this, what is this?
今日は来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming today!
まさかだよ、揃うとは思わんかった！
I never thought we'd actually get to perform together!
今日はちょっと初めてポルカちゃんに来ていただきました！
Today, we have Polka-chan here with us for the first time!
まさかお呼ばれされると思ってなかったんで恐縮でございます。
I honestly didn't expect to be invited, so I'm deeply honored.
いやこちらこそね、本当ありがとうございます！
No, thank you so much!
いやね、かわいい！
So cute!
いやいやありがとうございます！
Aw, thank you so much!
いやずっとなんかで絡みたいと思ってたからめちゃ嬉しいです。
I've always wanted to collab with you, so I'm super happy.
そうなんですよ。
Indeed.
でもいつづっといつもね誘いたいなって思っていたんですけど、なかなか誘いなくて今日初めて呼べて嬉しい！
I've always wanted to invite you, but never got the chance, so I'm so glad we could finally do it!
なになにこの子可愛いんだけど！
What is this, this kid is so cute!
あとね、あのポルカのね歌ってみた聴いてね一緒にやりたいなって思ったんだよね、嬉しいんだけど！
Also, I heard Polka's cover song and wanted to perform together, I'm so happy!
まさかね、この曲一緒に歌えると思わなかったからすごい嬉しいわ、本当にありがとうございます。
I never thought we'd get to sing this song together, so I'm really happy, thank you so much.
イエーイ！
Yay!
スクショ、スクショスクショ！
Screenshot, screenshot!
はい、もう本当にでもね、なんかすっげえ！
Yes, truly, but man, it's amazing!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
これからもね、何かで一緒に、あ、はい、こちら名刺、あ、こちらこそありがとうございます！受け取らせていただきます！
Let's do something together again—ah, yes, here's my business card—ah, thank you so much! I'll gladly accept it!
今日は本当に、え, あ, まだですよね？あ, な, なんとかちゃん, あ, すいません, 名刺を受け取ってちょっと帰るっていう, 名刺を受け取ると帰るっていう感じなんですね。
Today is really—wait, we're not done yet, right? Ah, so once you accept the business card, you just leave?
今日は本当におめでとうございますというわけでね、ありがとうございます！
Congratulations on today, thank you so much!
もう何度も言われてるでしょうけどね、本当すごい！今日もなんかいろんな方々がコラボしてくださって。
I'm sure you've heard this a lot, but it's amazing! Today too, so many people collaborated with you.
もうね、これが10曲目になるんですけど。
And this is already the 10th song.
すっげえな！
That's crazy!
すっげえな！まだまだ続きますので、あと2曲ぐらいかな？3曲ぐらいかな？5曲かな？
That's amazing! There's still more, another 2 songs maybe? 3 songs? 5 songs?
おいおい、じゃあまだ見てね！
Hey now, make sure to keep watching!
時間大丈夫なんかそんなん言って。
Are you sure you have enough time saying stuff like that?
じゃあありがとうございます、この後もね、え、君もそう、バイバイじゃないでしょ。
Well then thank you, stay tuned for the rest too—wait, you too, it's not time to say bye yet.
ポルカにどっちかっていうとバイバイ。
For Polka, it's more like bye-bye.
あ、ありがとうね！この後も楽しんでね！
Ah, thank you! Enjoy the rest of the show!
イエーイ！フー！
Yay! Woo!
行くよ！ポッピンキャンディ☆フィーバー！
Let's go! Poppin' Candy Fever!
あの日忘れた夢色も昨日零した涙色も
The dream-colored hues we forgot that day, the tear-colored hues we spilled yesterday—
有り体に言えないね
we can't simply put it plainly,
だからとっておきの魔法をかけよう
so let's cast a special magic.
キャラメル・キャンディ・チョコレート
Caramel, candy, chocolate—
お洒落でカワイイティタイムは
stylish and cute tea time
なんか疲れちゃいそうだし
might feel a bit tiring,
アゲアゲで行こうよ
so let's go high-energy!
コツは楽しんで楽しもうもちろん何でもありです
The trick is to enjoy and have fun, of course anything goes, right?
当然でしょ？
Naturally!
というかふざけたぶろぐらむがずっと続く
Or rather, this ridiculous program keeps going on and on.
行こう！
(Let's go!)
慣れちゃうね
We're getting used to it.
ずっと一緒だけど無邪気さは
Even so, our playful innocence
忘れないで君のBPM
is something we'll never lose—your BPM!
甘い匂いに釣られたなら
If you're lured in by the sweet aroma,
それじゃみんな 嘘げのマスク外して
then everyone, take off your fake masks!
パクッ！ころっ！
Munch! Roll!
ポッピンキャンディ☆フィーバー！弾けちゃいフレーバー
Poppin' Candy Fever! Bursting flavor,
Party Party なんです！ Shall We Dance? (Dance!)
Party Party it is! Shall We Dance? (Dance!)
なんちゃって☆フィーバー！？
Just kidding☆ Fever!?
兎も角さあ わっしょいわっしょい踊り明かそう (あそれ よいよ)
Rabbit or horn, let's dance the night away! (Here we go, yo!)
ポッピンキャンディ☆アップル！？ ねえ聞いてよDreamer!
Poppin' Candy Apple!? Hey, listen to me, Dreamer!
Check it! Check it! なんです！ Shall We Dance? (Dance!)
Check it! Check it! It is! Shall We Dance? (Dance!)
なんたって☆フィーバー！？
No matter what☆ Fever!?
テンションはMAXで もっともっととろけちゃうくらい (いっせーの で)
With maxed-out tension, until we melt even more (Ready, set, go!)
歌え！ (ちゃちゃちゃ！)
Sing! (Cha cha cha!)
踊れ！ (よいね！)
Dance! (Sounds good!)
笑え！ (わいわい！)
Smile! (Yay yay!)
鳴呼 いい感じ！ (はっはっはっ はっはっはっ)
Ah, feels great! (Ha ha ha, ha ha ha)
ねえもう一回！ (ちゃちゃちゃ！)
Hey, once more! (Cha cha cha!)
もういいかい？ (よいしょ！)
Ready yet? (Heave-ho!)
無問題！？ (はい優勝！)
No problem!? (Yes, you win!)
煌めく空をなぞったら
If we trace the glittering sky,
こんなちょっと寂しくなるね
it gets just a little bit lonely, doesn't it?
それじゃケーキもおひとつどう？
So how about another slice of cake?
なんだか笑ってきたね (おっけー！)
Somehow we've started laughing (Okay!)
ディンドンダンが響くような
Like ding-dong chimes echoing,
耳すませば君のBPM
if you listen closely, it's your BPM!
お腹の合図が聞こえたなら
If you hear the signal from your tummy,
それじゃみんな兎の祭典だ
then everyone, it's a rabbit festival!
準備は！？ (いただきます！)
Ready!? (Let's eat!)
はああ！？
Huh!?
ポッピンキャンディ☆フィーバー！しゅわしゅわフレーバー
Poppin' Candy Fever! Fizzy flavor,
Pachi Pachi なんです！ Shall We Dance? (Dance!)
Pachi Pachi it is! Shall We Dance? (Dance!)
なんちゃって☆フィーバー！？
Just kidding☆ Fever!?
兎も角さあ わっしょいわっしょい踊り明かそう (あそれ よいよ)
Rabbit or horn, let's dance the night away! (Here we go, yo!)
ポッピンキャンディ☆グレープ！？ こっち向いてDreamer!
Poppin' Candy Grape!? Look this way, Dreamer!
Hurry! Hurry! あっぷっぷ！ Shall We Smile! (Smile!)
Hurry! Hurry! Puff up! Shall We Smile! (Smile!)
なんたって☆フィーバー！？
No matter what☆ Fever!?
お味はMIXで もっともっと楽しんじゃって
The taste is mixed, let's enjoy it even more!
もういっちょいけるね はいおかわリ！
Can you take one more? Yes, seconds please!
いくぞー！
Let's go!
ポッピンキャンディ☆フィーバー！ 弾けちゃいフレーバー
Poppin' Candy Fever! Bursting flavor,
Party Party なんです！ Shall We Dance? (Dance!)
Party Party it is! Shall We Dance? (Dance!)
なんちゃって☆フィーバー！？
Just kidding☆ Fever!?
恥ずかしがり屋も わっしょいわっしょい踊り明かそう (あそれ よいよ)
Even the shy ones, let's dance the night away! (Here we go, yo!)
ポッピンキャンディ☆ピーチ！？ ねえ聞いてよDreamer!
Poppin' Candy Peach!? Hey, listen to me, Dreamer!
Check it! Check it! なんです！ Shall We Dance? (Dance!)
Check it! Check it! It is! Shall We Dance? (Dance!)
なんたって☆フィーバー！？
No matter what☆ Fever!?
テンションはMAXで もっともっとうるさいくらい (いっせーの で)
With maxed-out tension, until it's noisier than ever (Ready, set, go!)
歌え！ (ちゃちゃちゃ！)
Sing! (Cha cha cha!)
踊れ！ (よいね！)
Dance! (Sounds good!)
笑え！ (はっはっはっ)
Smile! (Ha ha ha)
鳴呼 いい感じ！ (はっはっはっ はっはっはっ)
Ah, feels great! (Ha ha ha, ha ha ha)
ねえもう一回！ (ちゃちゃちゃ！)
Hey, once more! (Cha cha cha!)
もういいかい？ (おまえかー！)
Ready yet? (You again!)
無問題！？ (うわーい！)
No problem!? (Yay!)
はい優勝！ (いえーい！)
Yes, you win! (Yeah!)
あー！
Ah—!
はー！あー！あー！
Ha—! Ah—! Ah—!
皆さん！おめでとう！ありがとうございます！
Everyone! Congratulations! Thank you so much!
がんばりましたー！
We did our best!
ということで、今日みこちと一緒に歌って踊ってもらいましたー！ありがとうございます！
And so, Miko-chi sang and danced with me today! Thank you so much!
おめでとう！おめでとう！呼んでくれて！
Congratulations! Congratulations for inviting me!
いや、嬉しいです。踊りも、可愛いなあ。今日も可愛いよなあ。
Man, I'm so happy. The dancing is so cute. You're so cute today too.
え、ありがとう！みこちも可愛いよ。可愛いよ。
Eh, thank you! Miko-chi is cute too. So cute.
え、そんなことないよ！可愛いね！そんなことないよ、ありがと可愛いね！
Eh, that's not true! You're cute! That's not true, thank you, so cute!
ていうかあれだよね、みこちとは新曲ぶり？こないだの。
I mean, you know, when was the last time with Miko-chi? Just the other day for the new song?
あ、そうね、みこちの新曲ライブにね、可愛い衣装で、そうそうそう。
Ah, right, for Miko-chi's new song live, with the cute outfits, yeah.
でも二人目はちょっと、初めてだよね？
But the two of us together like this is a first, right?
そう、そうなのよ。二人目はね、初めてなんですよ。意外とね。
Yeah, that's right. The two of us is a first. Surprisingly.
え、なんであやめータワミコのこと呼んでくれたの？
Eh, why did Ayame-chama invite Miko?
え、実はね、あの、ポッピンキャンディフィーバーを聞いた時に、すっごいにこちに合うって思ったんですよ。
Well, actually, when I heard "Poppin Candy Fever," I thought it would suit Miko-chi so much.
えー！だから一緒に歌いたいって思って誘っちゃった！やったー！ありがとう！
Eeh! That's why I wanted to sing it together and invited you! Yay! Thank you!
え、じゃああやめータワミコに懐き始めた来たという、そういうメッセージ、そういうメッセージなのよ？
Eh, then is it like Ayame-chama started getting attached to Miko, is that the message?
うん。あれ？
Yeah. Huh?
おともだち、おともだちチームみたいな感じではなく？
Not like an "animal friends" kind of vibe?
いやなんか、愛玩動物みたいな？あ、そういう感じなのね。愛玩動物みたいな？
Well, like a pet? Ah, so that kind of vibe. Like a pet?
ええ、やったー！
Yay!
え、なんか二人って意外と、カメラさ、ちょっと引きで見えますか？ピンクでね、意外と可愛いんですよ、二人。
Eh, also, can the camera show us from a bit further back? In pink, you know, the two of us are surprisingly cute.
ね、可愛い！ね、色合いが雪です。
Right, cute! The color scheme is Yuki (snow/Nakiri).
あとはあれだよね、鬼と、鬼か、みこだからね。おお？もしかしてこれ退治される側ですか？
And also, you know, it's an ogre and Miko. Oh? By any chance, is Miko the one being exorcised?
はー！鬼は外ー！福は内ー！やったー！おめでとう！
Ha! Ogre outside! Fortune inside! Yay! Congratulations!
え、この後も見てねー！
Eh, keep watching after this too!
わたしの一番かわいいところ 作詞・作曲 ヤマトショウ
Watashi no Ichiban Kawaii Tokoro (Lyrics & Music: Yamato Sho)
あれ気づいちゃいましたか？ 生れて30秒で最初に聞いた言葉は
Have you noticed already? The first words I heard 30 seconds after being born
当たり前にそりゃ覚えてないけど
naturally I don't remember them, of course,
あれ気付いちゃいましたか？
Did you notice it?
うまれて30秒で最初に聞いた言葉は
The first words I heard 30 seconds after birth
当たり前にそれ覚えてないけど嬉しいはず
Of course I don't remember, but I'm sure it made me happy.
今でもだいたいのことは変わってないっていうことだよ
It means most things haven't changed even now.
中身は変わっていますのでそのへんでも評価 （おねがい！）
My insides have changed, so evaluate that too! (Please!)
携帯のアンテナを光らせて
Making my phone's antenna glow
それが超キュートなあの頃だって知ってたしって言うか
I knew how super cute that was back then—or rather,
アンテナって何て言ってるようなそれに付き合ってくれるの
what kind of antenna is that? Thanks for putting up with it.
逆にでもわたしのどこが好き？
On the flip side, what do you like about me?
ねぇ！ねぇ！ねぇ！
Hey! Hey! Hey!
わたしたちの一番かわいいところに気付いてる
You've noticed the cutest thing about me!
そんな君が一番すごいすごいよ凄すぎる
You are the most amazing, amazing, way too amazing!
そして君が知ってるわたしが一番かわいいの
And the me you know is the cutest of all.
わたしもそれに気付いた
I realized that too!
だからそれかわいいあれかわいいなんて 誰かわいいそれかわいいなんて言わないでわたし以外なんてやだ
So don't go saying "that's cute" or "this is cute", or "who's cute?" or "that's cute"! I hate anyone other than me!
なんてありえない？
Isn't that impossible?
わたし気付いちゃいました
I've realized it!
毎日何十秒も褒められまくったお菓子は
Sweets praised for dozens of seconds every day
他よりちょっと甘くなるって
become a little sweeter than others,
前聞いたような
or so I heard before.
さすがあれなんか変だけど わたしは言われたいタイプでして
As expected, that's kind of weird, but I'm the type who wants to be told—
もっとわかりやすくしていいんだよ？
You can make it easier to understand, you know?
お待ちしてまーす おねがい！
I'll be waiting! Please!
何してもどんな顔見せてても
No matter what I do, no matter what face I make,
いつも超キュートだって確信してるのは
I'm convinced I'm always super cute—
なんだかさすを知らないタイプの運命の人なの？付き合ったりは無理ごめんなさい
Are you a type of soulmate I didn't know? Date? No way, sorry!
逆にでもそれより楽しいよ
On the flip side, it's even more fun!
ねぇ！ねぇ！ねぇ！
Hey! Hey! Hey!
わたしたちの一番かわいいところをよく見てる
You look closely at the cutest things about us!
そんな君が本当に超ラッキーな人すぎる
You're truly such a super lucky person.
そして君が何年たってもそう思えるようにわたしはそれに気付いた
And so that you can feel that way years from now, I realized it!
会えないときもどんな表情してるかとか
Even when we can't meet, what kind of expression you're making...
気持ち悪くないくらい想像しちゃうかな
I end up imagining it just enough not to be creepy.
それかわいい あれかわいいって本当にかわいいって言ってって
Saying "that's cute", "this is cute", saying "you're really cute"—
わたしたちの一番かわいいところに気付いてる
You've noticed the cutest thing about us!
そんな君が一番すごいすごいよ凄すぎる
You are the most amazing, amazing, way too amazing!
そして君が知ってるわたしが一番かわいいのわたしもそれに気付いた
And the me you know is the cutest of all. I realized that too!
だからそれかわいいあれかわいいなんて 誰かわいい それかわいいなんて言わないで わたし以外なんてやだ
So don't go saying "that's cute" or "this is cute", or "who's cute?" or "that's cute"! I hate anyone other than me!
わたしたちの一番かわいいところに気付いてる
You've noticed the cutest thing about us!
そんな君が一番すごいすごいよ凄すぎる
You are the most amazing, amazing, way too amazing!
そして君が知ってるわたしが一番かわいいの わたしもそれに気付いた
And the me you know is the cutest of all. I realized that too!
だからそれかわいいあれかわいいなんて 誰かわいいそれかわいいなんて言わないで わたし以外なんてやだ なんてありえない
So don't go saying "that's cute" or "this is cute", or "who's cute?" or "that's cute"! I hate anyone other than me, as if that's possible!
みんなありがとうございます！来てくれてね！
Thank you everyone! Thanks for coming!
あやめ先輩！ よっしゅね！おめでとうございます！
Ayame-senpai! Yoshhune! Congratulations!
すりしー今日はちょっとねラミィちゃんとペコーラと、かなたんとりん来てもらいまして！
Today we invited Lamy-chan, Pekora, Kanatan, and Marin to come join!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
てかさしかもこのこっちのお二人は初めて3Dなんだよね
And besides, these two over here are in 3D for the first time!
そうなんですよ！だから来てほしかったメンバーなので来てよ本当嬉しいです！
That's right! That's why they were members I wanted to come, so I'm really happy they came!
一応ね一番かわいいって思ってくれてるっていう、可愛いメンバー！可愛いメンバー！みんな可愛い！
They're cute members who think I'm the cutest! Cute members! Everyone is cute!
一番誰が一番可愛いかみたいな！
Like, who is the cutest?!
そのTikTok、あの曲さっきね
That TikTok song earlier—
TikTokで流行ってる曲をね、ちょっとね
The song that's popular on TikTok, we...
あ、ベットネコも…え、何じゃない？
Ah, Bed Neko too... wait, isn't it?
流行りに、流行りについていけてる、うちら。
We're keeping up with the trends!
え、すごくない？
Right? Isn't that amazing?
しかもね、気づいたんですけど…
And you know what I just realized?
このメンバー、赤と…青がね…
Among us members, Red and... Blue...
めちゃ一緒、二人で！見て見て見て！
We match so much! Look, look, look!
え、すごない？同い年なの、青組。
Right? We're the same age, the Blue team!
え、すごーい！え、すごっ！
Whoa, amazing! Whoa, that's incredible!
え、こっち…え、でもほら、なんか、あんな感じ
Wait, over here... but hey, look, like...
かわいい、可愛いよ、うちら、ほら。
Cute! We're cute too, look!
え、初々しい…やばいね、やばいわ、これ…
So fresh... this is crazy, so cute...
ちょっと…これはちょっと鬼と…鬼と…？
Wait... this is a bit... Oni and... Oni...?
いや、許さないっすよ！ちょっと！
No way, I won't forgive you! Wait!
赤と…よっ、よっ…なんの？え、なにこれ？
Red and... Yo, yo... What is this?
強っ！すご！やば、やばい！うちらの青組強すぎる！
So strong! Our Blue team is too strong!
え、帰りましょっか！帰りましょっか！帰りましょっか！
Hey, shall we go home?!
全員やるんだ、全員やると…ものの見事に、な…
We're all doing it? If everyone does it...
あの、ものを、ものをロスしすぎるな。
Uh, don't waste things too much!
あれ？あれ？グッズ紹介あるよーー！バイバーイ！
Huh? Huh? There's merch intro! Bye-bye!
お待たせしました！
Thank you for waiting!
グッズ紹介のお時間でーす！
It's time for the merchandise introduction!
ということで、えー、皆さんお気づきかと思いますが、
With that said, I'm sure you've all noticed,
え、なきりあやめ活動4周年記念が…
Nakiri Ayame's 4th anniversary...
でまーーす！やったーー！みんなお待たせなの嬉しいお知らせですよーー！
Is out! Yay! Here's happy news for you!
ということで、グッズ紹介していきましょう！まずわ！こちら！
So let's introduce the merch! First up!
どーーーん！見てください！ワイドラバーマットです！じゃじゃーーん！
Ta-da! Look! A wide rubber mat! Ta-da!
こちらはね、ひら先生に描き下ろししていただきました。めちゃくちゃ可愛いラバーマット描いていただきました！ありがとうございます！
Illustrated by Hira-sensei. So cute!
そしてそして、まだありますよ！そして続いて、こちら！
And there's still more! Next up!
アクリルジオラママスタンドです！めちゃこれかわいいでしょ！せんちゃ先生に描き下ろしいただきました！ありがとうございます！めちゃかわいいよ！
An acrylic diorama! Illustrated by Sencha!
そしてそして！まだまだありますよ！次はこちら！
There's still more! Next is this!
ステンレスサーモタンブラーです！アクリルジオラマと同じせんちゃ先生に書いていただきました！めちゃくちゃ可愛いよ！冷たいお水飲んでからさ、みんな、あの水分補給は大事だと思うので、ぜひ使ってください！
A stainless thermos tumbler! Drawn by Sencha!
そしてそして！まだありますよ！そして続きまして、こちら！
And still more! Continuing with this!
ぽよよティッシュカバーです！みて！これ超可愛くないですか！余の手元にぽよよがあるのでちょっと…はい、やばっ、可愛いね！
A Poyoyo tissue cover! Look how cute!
こちらのぽよよのティッシュカバーがでまーーす！めちゃくちゃ可愛い！お部屋に置いて、ティッシュって日常的に使うと思うので、ぜひお部屋に置いて使ってほしいなって！
This Poyoyo tissue cover is out! So cute!
はい、ということでですね、さらにさらに大事なことを言い忘れちゃったんですけど、シチュエーションボイス、デビュー記念お花見デートもちゃんとついてきますよ！
And I forgot to mention the situation voice date!
そしてそしてですね、数量限定バージョンは、余の直筆サインと、複製メッセージ入りポストカードがついてきまーーす！数量限定なのでお早めに！お早めにお願いします！
The limited version comes with a signed postcard!
通常バージョンはですね、余の複製サインと、複製メッセージ入りポストカードとなっています！ぜひみなさんゲットしてください！
The regular version comes with a printed sign!
そして数量限定と通常バージョンも、特典ではですね、余のASMRボイス、お花見の後デートがついてきまーーす！はじめての試しなんですけど、ぜひ聞いていただけると嬉しいです！
Plus an ASMR post-viewing date voice!
ということでね、みんなライブどうでしたか？みんな可愛かったでしょ！みんな歌って踊って頑張ってくださったのでね、本当に大満足です！うれしいです、本当にね！
How was the live? Everyone did their best!
また新しくなってね、うれしー。
It's all new now, I'm so happy.
このあとは？
And after this...?
なんと！なんとなんとですよ！
What? What do you know!
メンバーシップ限定の配信があります！ちょこっとあります。
There's a membership-exclusive stream! Just a little bit.
見てください！ぜひ。
Please check it out, definitely.
えー、そちらをね、あの、夏、夏といえば？
Um, for that... um, su-, speaking of summer?
夏といえば、あの衣装が！見られるかもしれないよー！？
Speaking of summer, that outfit might be seen!?
えー、ということで、ぜひあのメンバーシップ限定の配信も見てくれると嬉しいです！
So um, I'd be super happy if you check out the membership-exclusive stream!
ということでぜひみんなグッズ買ってね！
So everyone please buy the merch!
ばいばーい！
Bye-bye!
白鬼あやめ 4周年 Happiness to you
Nakiri Ayame 4th Anniversary: Happiness to you